Herman Combrink

herman.combrink@gmail.com +64211440682

Summary

I am an experienced and driven solutions architect and developer with more than 10 years' experience within financial, insurance and telecommunication industries. I have a strong background in developing software, leading development teams and architectural designs. My experience ranges from web development, mobile applications, integration development, business intelligence and data warehousing.

I have a strong focus in coordinating client/business needs and translating that into effective solutions within a team environment while being sensitive to deadlines and other business constraints.

Career History

Cloud Solution Architect at COMS

Nov 2019 - Present (1 year and 2 months)

I am currently contracted to COMS as a cloud solutions architect for Azure.

In this role I am responsible for legacy migration and new infrastructure setup.

Part of this is budget control, security compliance and devops setup.

I also have a coding responsibility where I am active developing on the cloud native solution running in Azure. I currently have 1 intermediate developer assisting me in the development side.

Data Team Leader at TalkingTech

Mar 2017 - Nov 2019 (2 years and 8 months)

Started out as a technical lead for the core team, and transitioned into the data team lead where I took responsibility for data availability including all production databases, data compliance and data warehousing and reporting.

I had a team varying from 4 to 2 people over the course of my employment.

This included the senior DBA, and data protection officer.

Focused on delivering data warehousing solutions and enabling business with self-service business intelligence.

 Delivering bespoke projects with .Net Core services to Vodafone Australia and HSBC UK within the core

development team.

· Facilitation of the UK reporting team and NZ development team and coordination of projects.

Lead Software Developer at MyBucks

Jul 2014 - Mar 2017 (2 years and 8 months)

Played a key role as part of the development team as a team leader and architect in delivering loan management

systems with exposing API's to 3rd party vendors and delivering web solutions to the business serving 13 different

organizational units ranging from South Africa to Spain EU.

· Acted as a lead developer role in delivering the automated mobile application in Kenya called Haraka where we used

XGBoost decision trees to analyze and predict real-time risk, and Neo4J graph technology to counter fraud. The

application used google firebase and other cloud technologies to pay out loans Nano loans to mobile wallets every

30seconds with a 90% on-time collection rate.

Senior Software Engineer at OUTsurance (YOUI)

Feb 2012 - Jul 2014 (2 years and 5 months)

I was focused on delivering mobile applications both internal and the public using PhoneGap on both Android and IOS.

- · Also served as a team member on delivering home loan insurance applications.
- Delivering IBM Universe development solutions as part of the backing database solution for the company.

SENIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER at ISIXTY SOFTWARE

Jan 2010 - Jan 2012 (2 years)

 Designed and delivered Windows-based solutions for financial, commercial domestic insurance products catering

for policy management, re-insurance and claim control.

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER / OWNER at SUPERNATURAL TECHNOLOGIES

Mar 2009 - Jan 2010 (10 months)

Work as a contractor for FinRite mobile insurance. During this time a developed and designed mobile insurance

call centre software to drive a multi-tenant solution for the company with a strong audit trail to align with

industry compliance.

SYSTEM INTEGRATION ENGINEER / JAVA DEVELOPER at AFRICANPULSE MOBILE SOLUTIONS

Feb 2007 - Apr 2009 (2 years and 2 months)

Implementation of IVR and Voicemail server installations within major Telco providers within Southern Africa

ranging from South Africa, Botswana, Namibia and Mozambique.

 Developed IVR based call flows to bespoke solutions for clients and developed the company website

JUNIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER at 3FIFTEEN

Feb 2006 - Nov 2006 (9 months)

· Played a part in a development team developing a solution for vehicle financing using C#, SQL and BizTalk

Skills

C#, SQL, Angular, .NetCore, Werescape, CSS, JQuery, TypeScript, NoSQL, Redis, MongoDB, MSSQL, Python, NodeJS, Git, Mecurial, Jenkins, TeamCity, PowerShell, Bash, RabbitMQ, .NetFramework, Agile, Scrum, Kanban, SOLID, TDD, OWASP, HTML, Android, Java, OLAP, PowerBI, Team Leadership, Vue.JS, Microsoft Azure, Microsoft Azure Active Directory, Azure Service Bus Administration, Microsoft SQL Server, Golang, Data Warehousing, WhereScape Red, Microsoft Power Business Intelligence, Teamcity Software, Budget Management, DevOps, Design

Education

DIPLOMA INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY from TSWANE UNIVERSITY OF TECHNOLOGY

Graduated 2005

Honours